<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="jdaumeyer.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="jdaumeyer.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-05-02T19:04:13-04:00</updated><id>jdaumeyer.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Jackson Daumeyer</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Font Development</title><link href="jdaumeyer.com/work/2021/03/06/work-post-number-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Font Development" /><published>2021-03-06T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-03-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>jdaumeyer.com/work/2021/03/06/work-post-number-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="jdaumeyer.com/work/2021/03/06/work-post-number-1.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;smallcaps&quot;&gt; I have always had a passion for typography.&lt;/span&gt; I’ve loved the way that letters look, so in school I took the opportunity to develop a font of my own. &lt;!-- excerpt --&gt;Nitrogen is actally the second font that I made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blear.png&quot; alt=&quot;Picture of blear font&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;blear&quot;&gt;Blear&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first font was a project called &lt;em&gt;Blear&lt;/em&gt;, which was a small font I made to get used to using FontForge for developing fonts. And when I say small, I mean small; &lt;em&gt;Blear&lt;/em&gt; was a raster font that was 3 pixels wide and 4 pixels tall. Being so small it was nearly impossible to read, but it was never really meant to be read. I made the font so small so that it would be super easy to make glyphs so that I could quickly get into finalizing a font. This gave me the opportunity to work with FontForge’s kerning and exporting tools. In that way it was a success and it was a lot of fun to work on. If you want to check it out, which I wouldn’t recomend actually using it, you can find it on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/modernTypewritter/blear&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/nitrogen.png&quot; alt=&quot;Picture of Nitrogen font&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;nitrogen&quot;&gt;Nitrogen&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nitrogen&lt;/em&gt; was the first font that I made with the idea of it being an actual font. I started off with drawing out some initial sketches on paper although sadly I have since lost them. What came out of those sketches was a Geometric Sans-serif font. The basis for the font was a lowercase letter ‘n’ that I drew. The curved shape and left running terminal became a motif for the rest of the font. This ‘n’ then became the reason I named the font ‘Nitrogen’. After making the ‘n’, I began making vector illustrations of other letters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These started out as rough skecthes as I draged around shapes experimenting with different letter forms. This is when I learned that the process of desinging a font is extremely iterative. It is a constant fight between several aspects, readability, style, uniquness and consistency. Every gylph is a balance of this attributes and the only way to achieve this balance is by trial and error. However, in &lt;em&gt;Nitrogen&lt;/em&gt;, some of these glyphs don’t have a great balance in my opinion. These are glyphs that if I were to go back and work on the font again, I would most certainly change. These glyphs are mainly the ‘z’ and ‘s’, I feel that I gave too much into the sharp design of &lt;em&gt;Nitrogen&lt;/em&gt; with them and they’ve suffered from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However despite its roughness, &lt;em&gt;Nitrogen&lt;/em&gt; is still a project I am very proud of. It was my first time creating a vector font and that definitely shows, but I still looks good. If you want to check it out, files for it can be found on my &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/modernTypewritter/nitro&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; as well.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="work" /><category term="project" /><category term="typography" /><summary type="html">I have always had a passion for typography. I’ve loved the way that letters look, so in school I took the opportunity to develop a font of my own.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="jdaumeyer.com/assets/images/nitrogen.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="jdaumeyer.com/assets/images/nitrogen.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>